It's a touchy subject.
这是个敏感话题。
Talking socially about money can make people feel uncomfortable.
在社交场合谈论金钱会让人感到不自在。
But at work, have a conversation about how much people earn, and things can not only get awkward, but, in some cases, it can get you sacked.
而在职场中，聊起收入这件事，不仅会让场面变得尴尬，在某些情况下，甚至还会让你丢了工作。
According to a survey by the Trades Union Congress, 1 in 5 workers "have been told they can’t talk about their pay at work".
英国职工总会的一项调查显示，五分之一的员工“被告知不能在工作场合谈论自己的薪资”。
This, concludes the TUC, indicates how common pay secrecy or 'gagging' clauses are in employment contracts.
职工总会称，这一数据表明薪资保密或“封口”条款在雇佣合同中十分普遍。
'Pay secrecy clauses are a get out of jail free card for bad bosses,' said TUC general secretary Frances O'Grady.
职工总会秘书长弗朗西斯·奥格雷迪表示：“薪资保密条款是无良老板的‘免罪符’。
'They stop workers from challenging unfair pay, allow top executives to hoard profits and encourage discrimination.
这些条款阻止员工对不公平薪酬提出质疑，纵容高管隐藏收益，还会助长歧视现象。
More openness about wages is essential to building fairer workplaces.'
薪资信息更加公开透明，对于打造更公平的职场环境至关重要。”
So, should we talk about how much we earn?
那么，我们到底该不该谈论自己的收入呢？
It's not so simple.
事情并没有那么简单。
Even without the contractual obligations, people may still be reluctant.
即便没有合同条款的约束，人们可能依然不愿提及此事。
"I personally have found it's better not looking and not knowing," Tracy Jordan, an HR professional, told the BBC.
人力资源从业者特雷西·乔丹告诉BBC：“就我个人而言，我觉得眼不见为净。
"Even if you feel you are paid a fair wage, there will always be someone that you perceive is doing a lesser job and is earning more.
就算你觉得自己的薪水很公道，也总会发现有人干的活更少，拿的钱却更多。
Rather than feeling perpetually dissatisfied, I think ignorance can be bliss."
与其一直心怀不满，不如无知是福。”
Money is tied up with complex emotions, Brianna McGurran, a money expert at the personal finance blog NerdWallet, told the New York Times. It involves emotions like shame, success and fear of failure.
个人理财博客“书呆子钱包”的理财专家布里安娜·麦古兰在接受《纽约时报》采访时表示，金钱往往与复杂的情绪挂钩，其中包含羞耻感、成就感以及对失败的恐惧。
It also influences how people view you. People's money is tied to their self-worth.
金钱还会影响他人对你的看法，人们会将收入与自我价值绑定。
As a result, culturally, it can be bit of a taboo.
因此，从文化层面来讲，谈论金钱算得上是一个禁忌话题。
But all that may change.
但这一切或许都将改变。
First of all, pay secrecy clauses are unenforceable in the UK due to the UK Equality Act 2010.
首先，根据英国《2010年平等法案》，薪资保密条款在英国不具备法律效力。
An employee must always be able to find out if they are being discriminated against in terms of pay.
员工有权查明自己是否遭遇了薪酬歧视。
In addition, The European Union is considering new legislation on pay transparency in order to reduce gender pay, earnings and pension gaps.
此外，欧盟正考虑出台有关薪资透明度的新法规，以缩小性别薪酬差距、收入差距以及养老金差距。
So, for better or worse it may be something we all have to get used to.
所以，无论好坏，这都是我们所有人不得不去适应的趋势。
Over time, talking about our salaries may become just another matter for small talk.
假以时日，谈论薪资或许会成为日常闲聊中的又一个话题而已。